<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="cC967733-BB9C-11F0-1504-09173F13E4C5" xml:lang="en-us">
   <title>Basic Layout for the Information Screens</title>
   <prolog>
      <author>Metapercept</author>
      <critdates>








      
         <created date="2025-11-07+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-05-05"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role" platform="web" product="metR-Soul-Streator_Discipline"/>
         <keywords>
            <keyword/>
            <indexterm/>
            <indexterm/>
         </keywords>
         <othermeta name="title" content=""/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc" content=""/>
      </metadata>
      <resourceid appid="" appname="" id="" ux-source-priority="topic-and-map"/>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <p>The information screens have a standard layout.<fig id="fig_f12_rsj_fcc">
            <image href="media/image1.jpg"
                   placement="break"
                   align="center"
                   scale="50"
                   id="image_g12_rsj_fcc"/>
         </fig>
      </p>
      <p>Top Bar:  Shows the bottles counted per hour, and the percentage of pack, missing bottles, and rejects.</p>
      <p>Bottom Bar:  The buttons are described from left to right:</p>
      <p>Press the “Jupiter” button to view the Start / Main menu.  (See Section 4.)  The Start / Main menu provides access for logging into the system.  </p>
      <p>The first two buttons—Machine and Section—are also included on the Start/Main menu. <ul id="ul_gzc_5sj_fcc">
            <li>Machine screen is used to access diagnostics, and to shut down and start up the
               computer. (See Section 4.5.)</li>
            <li>Section screen displays information for a specific section. (See Section 3.) </li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>The other buttons open these information screens:<ul id="ul_b4x_xsj_fcc">
            <li>Rejects screen (Section 2.1) shows the last rejects and reject statistics.</li>
            <li>Transport screen (Section 2.2) opens graphs showing container information while the
               containers are on the conveyor.</li>
            <li>Dashboard screen displays alarms (Section 2.3).</li>
            <li>Overview screen shows all warnings, alarms, and rejects (Section 2.4).</li>
            <li>Distribution screen provides data on the x and y axes (Section 2.5).</li>
            <li>Lean screen displays lean data for each section (Section 2.6).</li>
            <li>Diameter screen shows the diameter measurements of each section (Section 2.7).</li>
            <li>Temperature screen shows the calculated temperatures of the containers at the camera
               position (Section 2.8). </li>
            <li>Tuning screen displays the vertical glass distribution of all containers on one
               screen (Section 2.9). </li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>The following items are located on the far right of the bottom bar:<ul id="ul_y4t_jtj_fcc">
            <li>RejectIndicator. Shows whether the reject is turned on or off. Press the indicator
               to manually reject one or more sections.<fig id="fig_ysj_rvj_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image2.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         id="image_zsj_rvj_fcc"
                         align="center"/>
               </fig>
            </li>
            <li>CameraSelection. Press the button to see the images for each camera. Choose between
               Camera 1, Camera 2, Camera 3, etc.<fig id="fig_r13_tvj_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image3.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         id="image_s13_tvj_fcc"
                         align="center"/>
               </fig>
            </li>
            <li>Help?  Press this icon to display an explanation of the alarm dots on the
               Dashboard and Overview screens.<fig id="fig_odv_5vj_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image4.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         id="image_pdv_5vj_fcc"
                         align="center"/>
               </fig>
            </li>
            <li>Time and Date</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
   </body>
</topic>
