<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="cC97AF38-BB9C-11F0-1508-09173F13E4C5" xml:lang="en-us">
   <title>Rejects Screen  </title>
   <prolog>
      <author>Metapercept</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-07+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-05-05"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role" platform="web" product="metR-Soul-Streator_Discipline"/>
         <keywords>
            <keyword/>
            <indexterm/>
            <indexterm/>
         </keywords>
         <othermeta name="title" content=""/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc" content=""/>
      </metadata>
      <resourceid appid="" appname="" id="" ux-source-priority="topic-and-map"/>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <p>The Rejects Screen shows information on the last bottles that are rejected, and some reject
         statistics. <fig id="fig_rf4_zvj_fcc">
            <image href="media/image5.jpg"
                   placement="break"
                   align="center"
                   scale="50"
                   id="image_sf4_zvj_fcc"/>
         </fig>
      </p>
      <p>Use the new buttons in bottom middle of the screen for the following actions:</p>
      <p>Images: Scroll through the images with the arrow keys, or press on the image. Press
         on the top or bottom of the image to scroll up and down. On the navigation bar to the right
         of the containers:<ul id="ul_wf1_cwj_fcc">
            <li>Press the circle icon (top image in the expanded icon box) to show the measurement
               regions.</li>
            <li>Press the camera icon (middle image) to view the images of another camera.</li>
            <li>Press the squares icon (bottom image) to change how the images are positioned on the
               screen.</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Timeframe: Use the three buttons on the left top to select the timeframe of the
         rejects: the current shift, one hour, or the last 20 minutes. This selection influences all
         information shown on this screen, including the images and statistics.</p>
      <p>Rejector: With the three buttons at the top right of the screen, you can:<ul id="ul_prc_gwj_fcc">
            <li>Turn Store Images Off and the Rejector Off.</li>
            <li>Turn Store Images On and the Rejector Off.</li>
            <li>Turn Store Images On and the Rejector On. Do this to test the setup of the system.
               Images are stored, but the bottles are not removed from the conveyor with the
               Rejector.</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>The list shows the camera that has caused the rejection (camera 1,2,3,4 etc.), the reject
         date and time, the section, the article number, and information on the cause of the
         rejection. Scroll through the list using the icons in the middle of the screen (go to top,
         one up, one down), or by pressing the top of the image (go up) or the bottom of the image
         (go down).</p>
      <p>Statistics: The Rejects (%) graph shows the percentage of bottles that are rejected
         (for all causes). A line at the bottom of the graph indicates if the rejector was on
         (white) or off (black).<ul id="ul_dyz_jwj_fcc">
            <li>The Worst Causes graph shows the causes of the rejects, e.g. inclusions, glass
               distribution. Press on one of the causes to show only the images of this cause in the
               list. To turn the selection off, press the &lt;Cancel&gt; button in the Worst
               Cavities title.</li>
            <li>The Worst Cavities graph shows the amount of rejects per cavity. You can press on
               one of the cavities and only show the images of this cavity in the list. To turn the
               selection off press the &lt;Cancel&gt; button in the Worst Causes title.</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Show Cycle: With the Show Cycle arrow buttons, you can see the bottle from the
         cavity before and after the reject. This is a fast way to check if the system has caught
         all bottles with a defect. For example, if a fin is detected, you can see if the bottles
         before and after have a fin or not.</p>
   </body>
</topic>
