<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="AdminWF-Adv">
   <title>Creating a Workflow Using Advanced Mode</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="administrator,engineering,management,external contractors,analyst"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>workflow-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form-builder</indexterm>
            <indexterm>workflow-engine</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form</indexterm>
            <indexterm>list-page</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>create-workflow</indexterm>
            <indexterm>configure-advanced-rules</indexterm>
            <indexterm>define-validations</indexterm>
            <indexterm>assign-conditional-approvals</indexterm>
            <indexterm>test-workflow</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>capital-program-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>mind-administration-guide</indexterm>
            <indexterm>enterprise-deployment</indexterm>
            <indexterm>web-platform</indexterm>
            <indexterm>infrastructure-software</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>Mind-Administration-Guide</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="CreateWFAdv"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="Advanced workflow creation covering prerequisites, advanced configuration and conditional approvals."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities"
                    content="workflow;form-builder;validations;conditional-approvals;roles"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:Capital-program-management;usecase:workflow-management;industry:glass-manufacturing"/>
         <othermeta name="tags"
                    content="create-workflow,define-validations,conditional-approvals"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase" content="advanced workflow configuration and validation"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <prereq>
         <ul>
            <li>The role of the logged in user has permission to create or edit workflows.</li>
         </ul>
      </prereq>
      <context>
         <p>The following procedure describes the steps to create a sample workflow using Workflow Management advanced activities. You can also use simple mode activities to create the workflow. <ph product="Exclude_PG_Content">For information on simple mode activities, refer to <xref href="CreateWFSimple.xml">Creating a Workflow Using Simple Mode</xref>.</ph>
         </p>
         <p>The example illustrates the following activities:</p>
         <ul>
            <li>
               <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> – The <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> action item enables you to associate a form and its field information to the workflow. Based on the field data of the form, the business decisions can be defined.</li>
            <li>
               <uicontrol>Condition Block</uicontrol> – The <uicontrol>Condition Block</uicontrol> action item enables you to define conditions to the workflow.
                </li>
            <li>
               <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> – The <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> action item enables you to define the stakeholders for the workflow to obtain appropriate business decisions.</li>
         </ul>
         <p>
            <uicontrol>Form Used</uicontrol>
            <ul>
               <li>Project Fund Transaction form</li>
            </ul>
         </p>
         <p>
            <uicontrol>Business Scenario Used</uicontrol>
         </p>
         <ul>
            <li>If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is more than $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol>.</li>
            <li>If the entered amount in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is less than $1000, then the approval of the <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol> is not required.</li>
         </ul>
      </context>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>
               <xref href="CreateWF.xml">Create a basic workflow.</xref>
            </p>
            <p>Alternatively, <xref href="EditWF.xml">edit a workflow</xref>.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To create a workflow using advanced features, in the toolbar, click <uicontrol>Switch to Advanced</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The
<uicontrol>ADVANCED ACTIVITIES</uicontrol> section is added to the <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> pane,  and the <uicontrol>Expressions</uicontrol>
tab is added to the canvas.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>You can define a form parameter to the workflow that can be used as a condition in the <uicontrol>Conditions Block </uicontrol> action item. To add a form parameter to the workflow, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> navigation pane, expand <uicontrol>ADVANCED ACTIVITIES</uicontrol>, and then drag the <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> action item to the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab. </p>
                  <p>The new stage item is displayed on the canvas. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> item. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> properties are displayed in the right pane, as illustrated in the following image: <fig>
                        <title>Workflow Get Form Data</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF4.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p> In the <uicontrol>Get Form Data</uicontrol> properties pane, provide the required information in the fields, as described in the following table: </p>
                  <p>
                     <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                 <entry>Description</entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Name</entry>
                                 <entry>Enter the name for the action. For example, enter <uicontrol>Get Fund Data</uicontrol>.</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Available Forms </entry>
                                 <entry>Select the required form. For example, select the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form. <p>Available options are forms that are defined in the application. <note> Based on the selected form, the associated field information of the form is displayed in the <uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> tab. </note>
                                    </p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Perform Operation After </entry>
                                 <entry>Click the required option:<ul>
                                       <li>Click <uicontrol>Any user completes action</uicontrol> to specify that if any of the action stakeholders transition the record to the next workflow stage, the record moves to the next workflow stage.</li>
                                       <li>Click <uicontrol>All user(s) complete action</uicontrol> to specify that all the action stakeholders must transition the record to the next workflow stage for the record to move to the next workflow stage.</li>
                                    </ul>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Input </entry>
                                 <entry>To select the workflow parameters, and perform the following steps:<ol>
                                       <li>Click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                                             <alt>List</alt>
                                          </image>.<p>The <uicontrol>RESOURCES</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
                                       </li>
                                       <li>Click <uicontrol>Workflow Data</uicontrol>. </li>
                                       <li>From the drop-down list, select <uicontrol>Associated Form</uicontrol> instance, and then click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. <p> Available options are parameters used to define the workflow for a form.</p>
                                       </li>
                                    </ol>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Output </entry>
                                 <entry> Select the required field information check box. <p>The selected field information is used to create a condition for the workflow. For example, select <uicontrol>Amount</uicontrol>. </p>
                                    <p>Available field information are associated with the form selected in the <uicontrol>Available Forms</uicontrol> field. </p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>You can define a condition for the selected form parameter using the conditions block. To add a <uicontrol>Condition Block</uicontrol> action item to the workflow, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> pane, expand <uicontrol>ADVANCED ACTIVITIES</uicontrol>, and then drag the <uicontrol>Advanced Conditions</uicontrol>  action item to the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Advanced Conditions Block</uicontrol> item is displayed on the canvas. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click <uicontrol>Advanced Conditions Block</uicontrol>  item. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the right pane, click  <uicontrol>Add Condition</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Alternatively, right-click the <uicontrol>Advanced Conditions Block</uicontrol>  item in the canvas, and then click <uicontrol>New If Else Branch</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> is displayed below the conditions block item as illustrated in the following image: <fig>
                        <title>Workflow Advanced If Else Branch</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF5.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                     <note> To delete an <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol>, right-click the <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> item, and then click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>. </note>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> item. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> properties are displayed in the right pane. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> box, enter the name for the condition. </p>
                  <p>For example, enter <uicontrol>Amount Greater than 1000</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Conditions Block</uicontrol> item. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the right pane, click <uicontrol>Add Condition</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Alternatively, right-click the <uicontrol>Conditions Block</uicontrol> item in the canvas, and then click <uicontrol>New If Else Branch</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> is displayed below the <uicontrol>Amount Greater than 1000</uicontrol> item as illustrated in the following image:<fig>
                        <title>Advanced Condition Block Example</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF6.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> item. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>If Else Branch</uicontrol> properties are displayed in the right pane. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> box, enter the name for the condition. </p>
                  <p>For example, enter <uicontrol>Else</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>You can associate a stakeholder who can perform the next workflow action based on the condition defined in the condition block. To add a stakeholder to the workflow, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> pane, expand <uicontrol>ADVANCED ACTIVITIES</uicontrol>, and then drag the <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> action item to the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> action item is displayed on the canvas. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> item. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Set Stake Holders</uicontrol> properties are displayed in the right pane, as illustrated in the following image:<fig>
                        <title>Stake Holders Settings</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF7.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> box, enter the name for the action. </p>
                  <p>For example, enter <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Perform Operation After</uicontrol> section, click the required option: </p>
                  <p>
                     <ul>
                        <li>
                           <uicontrol>Any user completes action</uicontrol>: To specify that if any of the action stakeholders transition the record to the next workflow stage, the record moves to the next workflow stage.</li>
                        <li>
                           <uicontrol>All user(s) complete action</uicontrol>: To specify that all the action stakeholders must transition the record to the next workflow stage for the record to move to the next workflow stage.</li>
                     </ul>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To connect workflow items to complete the business process, click the port at the item, and drag the port to the port of the required item as illustrated in the following image:</p>
            <p>
               <fig>
                  <title>Connecting Workflow Items</title>
                  <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF8.png" placement="inline"/>
               </fig>
               <note> By default, the port is located on the right of the box. To change the location of the port, right-click the new action item and click <uicontrol>Reverse Port</uicontrol>.</note>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To define conditions on the users performing a workflow action, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>Click the required port.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Workflow Connection</uicontrol> action is displayed on the right pane.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Perform Operation After</uicontrol> section, click the required option:</p>
                  <p>
                     <ul>
                        <li>
                           <uicontrol>Any user completes action</uicontrol>: To specify that if any of the action stakeholders transition the record to the next workflow stage, the record moves to the next workflow stage.</li>
                        <li>
                           <uicontrol>All user(s) complete action</uicontrol>: To specify that all the action stakeholders must transition the record to the next workflow stage for the record to move to the next workflow stage.</li>
                     </ul>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click the <uicontrol>Expressions </uicontrol> tab to define expressions for the workflows. </p>
            <p>An expression is a programming language. It is a combination of one or more constants, variables, functions, and operators that the programming language understands and computes to produce another value.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To create expression for the <uicontrol>Conditions Block</uicontrol> action item, in the <uicontrol>Expressions</uicontrol> tab, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expressions in this workflow</uicontrol>  section, click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Create Expression</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed. <fig>
                        <title>Creating Expression in Workflow</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF9.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Display Name</uicontrol> box, the default expression name is displayed as <uicontrol>AStringExpression</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Enter a new name for the expression being created. For example, enter <uicontrol>Check Amount</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Output Data Type</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the data type for the expression. </p>
                  <p> For example, select <uicontrol>Boolean</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> box, enter the description for the expression. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expression Tree</uicontrol> section, click <uicontrol>RootNode</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Resource Parameters</uicontrol> section, double-click the required default expression code for the Amount in $ field that is with the <uicontrol>Instance ID</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The default expression code is displayed in the <uicontrol>Expression Text</uicontrol> box as illustrated in the following image:<fig>
                        <title>Creating Expression Text</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF10.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expression Text</uicontrol> box, click and add the condition to the default expression code. </p>
                  <p>For example, edit the default expression code, according to the format illustrated in the following image: <fig>
                        <title>Expression Text</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF11.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click<uicontrol> Validate</uicontrol> to check the format and completeness of the edited expression. </p>
                  <p>On successful validation, the validation success message is displayed. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Check Amount</uicontrol> expression is added to the <uicontrol>Expressions in this workflow</uicontrol> section. </p>
                  <p>You can use the following example expression codes to change the condition for the workflow: <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="3">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="10%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="40%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="50%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Operator</entry>
                                 <entry>Expression</entry>
                                 <entry>Description</entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ==</entry>
                                 <entry> return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] == 1000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is EQUAL to $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>!= </entry>
                                 <entry> return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] != 1000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is NOT EQUAL to $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>&lt; </entry>
                                 <entry>return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &lt; 1000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is LESS THAN $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> &lt;= </entry>
                                 <entry>return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &lt;= 1000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is LESS THAN OR EQUAL to $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> &gt;= </entry>
                                 <entry> return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &gt;= 1000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form IS MORE THAN OR EQUAL to $1000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> &amp;&amp;</entry>
                                 <entry> return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &gt;= 1000 &amp;&amp; [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &lt;= 10000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is MORE THAN OR EQUAL to $1000 AND LESS THAN OR EQUAL to $10000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> || </entry>
                                 <entry> return [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &lt;= 1000 || [(_NewTest_GetFundData_amount)] &gt;= 10000; </entry>
                                 <entry> If the amount entered in the <uicontrol>Amount in $</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Project Fund Transaction</uicontrol> form is LESS THAN OR EQUAL to $1000 OR MORE THAN OR EQUAL to $10000, then the transaction must be approved by the <uicontrol>Director of Finance</uicontrol>. </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To create expression for the <uicontrol>Set Stake Holder</uicontrol> action item, in the <uicontrol>Expressions</uicontrol> tab, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expressions in this workflow</uicontrol>  section, click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Create Expression</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Display Name</uicontrol> box, the default expression name is displayed as <uicontrol>AStringExpression</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p> Enter a new name for the expression being created. For example, enter <uicontrol>Stakeholder Finance</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Output Data Type</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the data type for the expression output. For example, select <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> box, enter the description for the expression. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expression Tree</uicontrol> section, click <uicontrol>RootNode</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p> The <uicontrol>Expression Text</uicontrol> box is displayed as illustrated in the following image: <fig>
                        <title>Expression Code</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF12.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Expression Text</uicontrol> box, enter the expression code for the stakeholder. </p>
                  <p>For example, enter the expression code, according to the format illustrated in the following image: <fig>
                        <title>Validating Expression</title>
                        <image href="../../Screenshots/AWF13.png" placement="inline"/>
                     </fig>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol> to check the format and completeness of the entered code. On successful validation, the validation success message is displayed. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Stakeholder Finance</uicontrol> expression is added to the <uicontrol>Expressions  in this workflow</uicontrol> section. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click the <uicontrol>Workflow </uicontrol> tab.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To add the <uicontrol>Expression </uicontrol> to the <uicontrol>Amount Greater than 1000</uicontrol> action item, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow </uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Amount Greater than 1000</uicontrol> action item.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Amount Greater than 1000</uicontrol> item properties are displayed in the right pane.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Condition </uicontrol> box, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>RESOURCES </uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Expression</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the drop-down list, select the <uicontrol>Check Amount</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Available options are expressions defined in the <uicontrol>Expressions </uicontrol> tab.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To add the <uicontrol>Expression </uicontrol> to the <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol> action item, perform the following steps: </p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Workflow </uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol> action item.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Finance Administrator</uicontrol> item properties are displayed in the right pane.
                        </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Action Stake Holders</uicontrol> box, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>RESOURCES </uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Expression</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the drop-down list, select the <uicontrol>Stakeholder Finance</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Available options are expressions defined in the <uicontrol>Expressions</uicontrol> tab.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>View Stake Holders</uicontrol> box, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>RESOURCES </uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Expression</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the drop-down list, select the <uicontrol>Stakeholder Finance</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>Available options are expressions defined in the <uicontrol>Expressions </uicontrol> tab.</p>
                  <p>Optionally, you can create expressions to add a different view stakeholder.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The workflow is saved and listed on the <uicontrol>WORKFLOW LIST</uicontrol> page.</p>
         </li>
      </ol>
      <div>The workflow must now be published to be made available in the application. <ph product="Exclude_PG_Content">For information on publishing a workflow, refer to <xref href="PublishWF.xml">Publishing a Workflow</xref>.</ph>
      </div>
   </body>
</topic>
