<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="ElectricalSafety-E49C2B46" xml:lang="en">
   <title>Electrical Safety</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Metapercept</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-06+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-05-05"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role" platform="web" product="metR-Reality-Batch_1"/>
         <keywords>
            <keyword/>
            <indexterm/>
            <indexterm/>
         </keywords>
         <othermeta name="title" content=""/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc" content=""/>
      </metadata>
      <resourceid appid="" appname="" id="" ux-source-priority="topic-and-map"/>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <section>
         <hazardstatement id="HazardOfElectricalShockExplosionOrA-E5439A99" type="danger">
            <messagepanel>
               <typeofhazard>hazard of electric shock, explosion or arc flash</typeofhazard>
               <howtoavoid>
                  <sl>
                     <sli>Electrical equipment must be installed, operated, serviced, and
maintained only by qualified personnel.</sli>
                     <sli>The UPS system must be installed in a room with restricted access
(qualified personnel only).</sli>
                     <sli>Apply appropriate personal protective equipment (PPE) and follow
safe electrical work practices.</sli>
                     <sli>Turn off all power supplying the UPS system before working on
or inside the equipment.</sli>
                     <sli>Before working on the UPS system, check for hazardous voltage
between all terminals including the protective earth.</sli>
                     <sli>The UPS contains an internal energy source. Hazardous voltage
can be present even when disconnected from the utility/mains supply.
Before installing or servicing the UPS system, ensure that the units
are OFF and that utility/mains and batteries are disconnected. Wait
five minutes before opening the UPS to allow the capacitors to discharge.</sli>
                     <sli>A disconnection device (e.g. disconnection circuit breaker or
switch) must be installed to enable isolation of the system from upstream
power sources in accordance with local regulations. This disconnection
device must be easily accessible and visible.</sli>
                     <sli>The UPS must be properly earthed/grounded and due to a high leakage
current, the earthing/grounding conductor must be connected first.</sli>
                  </sl>
               </howtoavoid>
            </messagepanel>
         </hazardstatement>
         <hazardstatement type="danger">
            <messagepanel>
               <typeofhazard>Hazard of electric shock, explosion, or arc flash</typeofhazard>
               <howtoavoid>In systems where backfeed protection is not part of the
standard design, an automatic isolation device (backfeed protection
option or other device meeting the requirements of IEC/EN 62040–1 or UL1778 5th Edition – depending on which of the two
standards apply to your local area) must be installed to prevent hazardous
voltage or energy at the input terminals of the isolation device.
The device must open within 15 seconds after the upstream power supply
fails and must be rated according to the specifications.</howtoavoid>
            </messagepanel>
         </hazardstatement>
         <p id="WhenTheUPSInputIsConnectedThroughEx-E5439CD1">When the UPS input
is connected through external isolators that, when opened, isolate
the neutral or when the automatic backfeed isolation is provided external
to the equipment or is connected to an IT power distribution system,
a label must be fitted at the UPS input terminals, and on all primary
power isolators installed remote from the UPS area and on external
access points between such isolators and the UPS, by the user, displaying
the following text (or equivalent in a language which is acceptable
in the country in which the UPS system is installed):</p>
         <hazardstatement type="danger">
            <messagepanel>
               <typeofhazard>Hazard of electric shock, explosion, or arc flash</typeofhazard>
               <howtoavoid>Risk of Voltage Backfeed. Before working on this circuit:
Isolate the UPS and check for hazardous voltage between all terminals
including the protective earth.</howtoavoid>
            </messagepanel>
         </hazardstatement>
      </section>
   </body>
</topic>
