<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="cC9D921F-BB9C-11F0-2595-09173F13E4C5" xml:lang="en-us">
   <title>Start/Main Menu ➔Section Menu ➔Rejects Rejector Timing Screen</title>
   <prolog>
      <author>Metapercept</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-07+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-05-05"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role" platform="web" product="metR-Soul-Streator_Discipline"/>
         <keywords>
            <keyword/>
            <indexterm/>
            <indexterm/>
         </keywords>
         <othermeta name="title" content=""/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc" content=""/>
      </metadata>
      <resourceid appid="" appname="" id="" ux-source-priority="topic-and-map"/>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <p>To set the rejector timing:<ol id="ol_z22_bl3_fcc">
            <li>Press Distance to Reject (Rejector), and enter the distance between the main camera
               viewpoint on the conveyor and the rejector. Normally this value is only set during
               the installation of the system and does not need to be changed.</li>
            <li>Press Pulse Time, and enter the pulse time in milliseconds (the time the reject
               valve is activated).</li>
            <li>Press Blow Off, and select one of the sections to reject.</li>
            <li>If the reject pulse is too early, increase the Distance to Reject value. If the
               pulse is too late, decrease the value.</li>
            <li>Repeat these steps until the rejector functions correctly.<fig id="fig_yry_2l3_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image7.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         id="image_zry_2l3_fcc"
                         align="center"
                         scale="50"/>
               </fig>
               <fig id="fig_dq5_3l3_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image8.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         align="center"
                         id="image_eq5_3l3_fcc"
                         scale="50"/>
               </fig>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </p>
      <p>
         <note type="note" id="note_tdw_tl3_fcc"> In case the ISWatch system uses the forming
            machine rejector, and the machine reject pulse is connected to the ISWatch system, the
            Distance to Reject value can be calculated automatically by the system.</note>
         <ol id="ol_f5m_cm3_fcc">
            <li>Press Pulse Time, and enter the pulse time (the time the reject valve is
               activated).</li>
            <li>Press Start Procedure.</li>
            <li>Press Synchronization and select one section.</li>
            <li>Start rejecting bottles of this section with the forming machine reject (and ONLY
               one section). The ISWatch measures the distance during 5 rejects.</li>
            <li>Press Blow Off, and select one of the cavities/sections to reject.</li>
            <li>If the reject pulse is too early, increase the Distance to Reject value. If the
               pulse is too late, decrease the value.</li>
            <li>Repeat steps 5 and 6 until the reject system functions correctly.<fig id="fig_g5m_cm3_fcc">
                  <image href="media/image9.jpg"
                         placement="break"
                         align="center"
                         scale="50"
                         id="image_h5m_cm3_fcc"/>
               </fig>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </p>
   </body>
</topic>
