<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="XmlFormBuilder_FRMBLDR">
   <title>Creating a Form Using Form Builder</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="administrator,engineering,management,external contractors,analyst"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>form-builder</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form-designer</indexterm>
            <indexterm>config-plus</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form-library</indexterm>
            <indexterm>preview-service</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>designing-forms</indexterm>
            <indexterm>adding-questions</indexterm>
            <indexterm>setting-validation-rules</indexterm>
            <indexterm>preview-and-test</indexterm>
            <indexterm>saving-and-publishing</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>capital-program-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>end-user-forms</indexterm>
            <indexterm>testing-environment</indexterm>
            <indexterm>business-logic</indexterm>
            <indexterm>web-platform</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>Mind-Administration-Guide</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="Using Form Builder"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="How to use the Form Builder interface: create questions, set validation, preview forms and prepare them for publishing."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities"
                    content="question;validation-rule;preview;form-template;publish-button"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:capital-program-management;usecase:form-design-and-testing;industry:software"/>
         <othermeta name="tags" content="design,validation,preview,save,publish"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase" content="design-test-and-prepare-forms"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <context>The following procedure describes the steps to create a sample form for recording employee information. The example fields and options selected in the procedure are for instructional purposes.<p>The example illustrates the following controls:</p>
         <ul>
            <li>Section </li>
            <li>Automatically generated sequential numbers </li>
            <li>Text box </li>
            <li>Option buttons </li>
            <li>Drop-down list with options defined from a Library catalog </li>
            <li>Condition based form controls </li>
            <li>Static grid</li>
            <li>Set</li>
            <li>Picker and Picker Trigger </li>
         </ul>
      </context>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>In the module menu, click<uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>ADMINISTRATION</uicontrol> page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the navigation pane, expand the<uicontrol>Configuration Toolkit</uicontrol>folder, and then click<uicontrol>Form Builder</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>FORMS LIST</uicontrol>page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click<uicontrol>New</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>Two tabs,<uicontrol>GENERAL</uicontrol>and<uicontrol>DESIGN</uicontrol>are displayed. <p>The<uicontrol>GENERAL</uicontrol> tab enables you to define the form name (Header), and the module (Parent Module) where the form must be available in the application at runtime. </p>
               <p>The <uicontrol>DESIGN</uicontrol> tab displays the form structure. The  tab is divided into 3 panes, the left pane, center pane, and the right pane. The left pane lists the controls to design the form, the center pane displays the form structure and design of the form, and the right pane displays the control attributes.</p>
               <fig>
                  <title>Form Builder</title>
                  <image href="../../Screenshots/FormBuilder.png" placement="inline"/>
               </fig>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the <uicontrol>GENERAL</uicontrol> tab specify the form details. </p>
            <p>
               <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                  <tgroup cols="2">
                     <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                     <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                     <thead>
                        <row>
                           <entry>Field</entry>
                           <entry>Description</entry>
                        </row>
                     </thead>
                     <tbody>
                        <row>
                           <entry> Form ID </entry>
                           <entry> This determines the unique ID for the form. Rename the form according to the requirements.<note> The <uicontrol>Form ID</uicontrol> should have seven unique alphanumeric characters.</note>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <entry> Header </entry>
                           <entry> This denotes the text to be displayed as a Header to the form after being published. <p>For example, enter<uicontrol>Employee Details</uicontrol>.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <entry> Parent Module </entry>
                           <entry> This determines the module in the application where the XML form will be available. <p>For example, if the field is to be a library catalog, then select <uicontrol>Library</uicontrol> form from the <uicontrol>Parent Module</uicontrol> list.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <entry> Folder </entry>
                           <entry> This determines the folder location where the XML form will be available in the application. <p>Type the complete path of the folder using the '/' separator. </p>
                              <p>If the folder exists, then the form will be available under the existing folder. Otherwise, a New Folder will be created, and the form will be placed under that folder. </p>
                              <p>For example, you can enter <uicontrol>Resources/Employees</uicontrol> in the<uicontrol>Folder</uicontrol> box. This creates two folders named<uicontrol>Resources</uicontrol>and<uicontrol>Employees</uicontrol>. The<uicontrol>Employees</uicontrol>folder is created in the<uicontrol>Resources</uicontrol> folder in the<uicontrol>Library</uicontrol>module. </p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                     </tbody>
                  </tgroup>
               </table>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click the <uicontrol>DESIGN</uicontrol> tab.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the <uicontrol>DESIGN</uicontrol> tab, click <uicontrol>Switch to Advanced</uicontrol>. </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To view or modify the form attributes, click in the design area.</p>
            <p>The form attributes are displayed. </p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>COMMON ATTRIBUTES</uicontrol> section, the form attributes are displayed as described in the following table.</p>
                  <p>
                     <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Attribute</entry>
                                 <entry>Description</entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Name</entry>
                                 <entry>This specifies the form identification number/name. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> PrimaryKeyName </entry>
                                 <entry> This is a default value for the form and should not be modified in normal circumstances. <p>The primary key for this database container. This usually is an auto increment integer. When using the SmartFormGenerator, this field is autogenerated. </p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AllowAttachments</entry>
                                 <entry> This enables users to upload files to the form, if it is set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Header</entry>
                                 <entry> This is the text to be displayed as the header of the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ExcelFileName </entry>
                                 <entry> Specify the name of the template Excel file for bulk import or export of form information. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ParentModuleID</entry>
                                 <entry> This determines the module ID where the form needs to be published. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AllowExcelExport </entry>
                                 <entry> Allows export of form information into an Excel workbook, if set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowDetailsReport </entry>
                                 <entry> If set to <uicontrol>True</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>Detail Report</uicontrol> menu is added to the <uicontrol>Reports</uicontrol> menu option. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowListPageReport </entry>
                                 <entry> If set to <uicontrol>True</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>List Page Report</uicontrol> menu is added to the <uicontrol>Reports</uicontrol> menu option. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowGISMapView</entry>
                                 <entry> If this is marked as <uicontrol>True</uicontrol>, then a button to show <uicontrol>Map View</uicontrol> on the list page is available. This functionality is applicable only to List pages associated to forms enabled with Map controls. <ph product="Exclude_PG_Content">For information on enabling map controls, refer to<xref href="EnblMapCntrl.xml">Enabling Map Control in a Form Using Form Builder</xref>.</ph>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Width </entry>
                                 <entry> The width of the form. The default is to resize the form based on its contents; however, pixel values can be used. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> EnableAuditLog </entry>
                                 <entry> If set to <uicontrol>True</uicontrol>, the audit log is enabled on a form. This is used for auditing purposes. </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>ADVANCED ATTRIBUTES</uicontrol> section, the form attributes are displayed as described in the following table.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note> These attributes are available only when you are in the advanced mode.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Attribute</entry>
                                 <entry>Description</entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> TableName </entry>
                                 <entry> Every time a form is created, a table is also created in the database. This is the name of the table that can be specified for identification. If not specified, then the system generates a unique table name. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Attributes </entry>
                                 <entry> Define style attributes for formatting. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AttachmentsVisibility </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute sets the “default” visibility (collapsed / expanded) for the attachment control. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> CollapsibleAttachments </entry>
                                 <entry> Attribute to decide whether the attachments are collapsible. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> MinimumNumberOfAttachments </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute sets the minimum number of files that must be attached to a form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ValidateAttachmentOnAction </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute enables you to set an action that validates the minimum number of attachments in a form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> CaptionStyle </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute changes the caption style for all control containers in the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> DropIfExists </entry>
                                 <entry> This deletes the corresponding table in the database while publishing a form if it’s set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> LinkToControlViewName </entry>
                                 <entry> Specify the name of the database to reference for the link control. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> IsActive </entry>
                                 <entry> This creates a node in the navigation pane with the Header mentioned above if it’s set to True. If set to False, the system will not display this form in the user interface, however, it will still be available for APIs.</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> IsSearchable </entry>
                                 <entry> When set to True, information in the form can be searched from the <uicontrol>Enterprise Search</uicontrol> utility in the <uicontrol>Home</uicontrol> module. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> IsTemplate </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute is marked True when creating Document metadata. For other forms, the attribute is generally marked as False. If set to True, this form will not be available in the UI. This setting is used for forms that are only utilized in APIs.</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowInMyReports </entry>
                                 <entry> If set to False, the form will not be accessible to the <uicontrol>Ad-hoc Reports</uicontrol> feature. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowInStages </entry>
                                 <entry> ShowInStages is the basis for integrating the form into workflow. If ShowInStages is set to True then sections can be disabled based on the approval stage a form is in. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> GroupBy</entry>
                                 <entry> Based on the parameter specified here, the records in the list page will be grouped together. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> DisplayNew</entry>
                                 <entry> If the <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> icon needs to be made visible, then it should be set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> DisplayEdit </entry>
                                 <entry> If the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> icon needs to be made visible, then it should be set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> DisplayView </entry>
                                 <entry> If the <uicontrol>View</uicontrol> icon needs to be made visible, then it should be set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> DisplayDelete </entry>
                                 <entry> If the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> icon needs to be made visible, then it should be set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AllowExcelImport </entry>
                                 <entry> Allows import of form information from an Excel workbook, if set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AllowExcelExportTemplateWithData </entry>
                                 <entry> Allows export of form information into an Excel workbook template, if set to True. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ControlCaptionWidth </entry>
                                 <entry> Defines the width of all field captions in this form. The default is 150 pixels. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> FormKey </entry>
                                 <entry> This is used to specify what needs to be shown in the details column of <uicontrol>My Tasks</uicontrol>. This will be used only if a workflow for the form is enabled. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowValidationSummary </entry>
                                 <entry> If set to True, on saving a form, displays all the validation messages in an alert box, instead of showing next to the control. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> AllowOffline </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute permits a form to go as offline. By marking the attribute True, the form can be made offline. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ShowInPermissions </entry>
                                 <entry> Select True to enable permission settings on the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> EnableMailMerge </entry>
                                 <entry> Select True if mail merge should be enabled for the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ReportPageOrientation </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute sets the layout for the Details Page report. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ReportPageSize </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute sets page size as “A4” or “Letter” for <uicontrol>Details Page</uicontrol> report. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ListReportPageSize </entry>
                                 <entry> Select the report size of <uicontrol>List Page</uicontrol> report. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ExportReportFileName </entry>
                                 <entry> This attribute specifies the name of the file which is downloaded from a form page. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> EnableCopyAndEdit </entry>
                                 <entry> Select True to enable users to copy and edit the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> HideInAuditLog</entry>
                                 <entry> Select False to enable audit log on the form. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>SingleInstance</entry>
                                 <entry>Select True to display a single instance of this form.<p>If False is selected, a list page is displayed for this form.</p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To design the layout of the form, first create a section. A section provides a boundary in the design area to add controls.</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, expand <uicontrol>GROUP LAYOUT</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Section</uicontrol> to the design area. </p>
                  <p>The label <uicontrol>SECTION &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> is displayed in the design area.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the design area, click <uicontrol>SECTION &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>COMMON ATTRIBUTES</uicontrol> pane displays the attributes for the <uicontrol>SECTION &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> section control.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>To define the attributes of the section, enter information in the <uicontrol>COMMON ATTRIBUTES</uicontrol> section, as described in the following table.</p>
                  <stepresult>
                     <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Attribute</entry>
                                 <entry>Description</entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Caption </entry>
                                 <entry> This denotes the display name of the section. <p>For example, you can enter <uicontrol>Employee Details</uicontrol> for the section name to be changed from <uicontrol>SECTION &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Employee Details</uicontrol>.</p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Name </entry>
                                 <entry> This is an automatically generated name to identify the section and need not be modified. <p>This is also the name of the column in the database, and is used to derive the name of the HTML item that is rendered. </p>
                                    <p>For example, you can enter <uicontrol>EmployeeDetails</uicontrol> to change the name from <uicontrol>Section&lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>EmployeeDetails</uicontrol>. <note> No spacing is allowed in the entered name. </note>
                                    </p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> HelpToolTip </entry>
                                 <entry> You can enter the tool tip that should be displayed while mouse hover on the field's Help (‘?’) icon. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> HelpDescription </entry>
                                 <entry> You can enter the description that should be displayed when the field's Help (‘?’) icon is clicked. </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </stepresult>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Perform the following steps to add a text box.</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>SIMPLE INPUT CONTROLS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Single Line Text</uicontrol> into the section.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note> Drop a control within the confines of the section for the control to be displayed in the design area.</note>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click the <uicontrol>TextBox &lt;number&gt; </uicontrol> control and enter a title for the text box. For example, enter <uicontrol>Employee Name</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>
                     <p>The various attributes of the control are listed below:</p>
                     <table colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                           <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="30%"/>
                           <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="70%"/>
                           <thead>
                              <row>
                                 <entry>Attribute </entry>
                                 <entry>Description </entry>
                              </row>
                           </thead>
                           <tbody>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Caption </entry>
                                 <entry> This denotes the display name of the control. The name to render on the display surface. If the caption is not set, then the default caption is set to the Name attribute of the control. To set a control with no title, delete the caption. <p>For example, you can enter <uicontrol>Employee Name</uicontrol>.</p>
                                 </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Name </entry>
                                 <entry> This is a system generated name to denote the control. You need not modify this field; however, normally a form designer provides names that represent the meaning of the data in the field. Name attributes should not have spaces in them, and they must be unique throughout the form. The name field is used to create the underlying database column name and to derive the name of the rendered HTML item.</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> HelpToolTip </entry>
                                 <entry> You can enter the tool tip that should be displayed on mouse hover on the field's Help (‘?’) icon. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> HelpDescription </entry>
                                 <entry> You can enter the description that should be displayed when the field's Help (‘?’) icon is clicked. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Width </entry>
                                 <entry> This is used to set the width of a control in the user interface. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> Type </entry>
                                 <entry> This determines the options to select the type of control required in the form. For example, you can add a text box to a section and later change it to a drop-down list.</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry morerows="15"> Value </entry>
                                 <entry> You can specify a default value to be displayed in the control. Also, you can use the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> field to retrieve system level information during display processing. The supported format values include the following: </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CURRENTUSER} - Displays the user name of the logged in user. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CURRENTUSERNAME} - Displays the first name of the logged in user. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CURRENTDATE} - Displays the current date. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CURRENTDATETIME} - Displays the current date and time. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CURRENTTIME} - Displays the current time. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {PROJECTNAME} - Displays the name of the project. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {PROJECTCODE} - Displays the project code. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CONTRACTNAME} - Displays the name of the contract </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {CONTRACTCODE} - Displays the contract code. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {PRIMECONTRACTOR} - Displays the prime contractor of the contract. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {_FORMULA: formula} </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {_REQUEST: state info field} </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {_DB: db expression} </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> {_Picker: [name of the picker that is defined in this xml]}</entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> "any static text" - Displays the text entered here. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> ReadOnly</entry>
                                 <entry> If set to True, the data in the form is made read only and the data cannot be modified by the end user. </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                 <entry> MaxLength </entry>
                                 <entry> Sets the maximum number of characters that can be entered in the text box. </entry>
                              </row>
                           </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To add a Radio Button, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>SIMPLE INPUT CONTROLS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Radio Button List</uicontrol> into the section. </p>
                  <p>By default, two radio buttons are displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click the radio button group. </p>
                  <p>The attribute pane displays the radio button control attributes.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> attribute, enter a title for button set. For example, you might enter <uicontrol>Gender</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>DataSource</uicontrol>, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Data Source Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed. <ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Display</uicontrol> column, enter title for each button option. <p>For example, you might label <uicontrol>Option 1</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Option 2</uicontrol> as <uicontrol>Male</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Female</uicontrol> respectively.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column, enter value for each option. For example, you might enter <uicontrol>Male</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Female</uicontrol> for <uicontrol>Option 1</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Option 2</uicontrol> respectively.</li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Perform the following steps to add a text box with a large layout. For example, you might use one to allow users to type in an address.</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>SIMPLE INPUT CONTROLS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Multi Line Text</uicontrol> into the section.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>TextArea &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> in the design area.</p>
                  <p>The attribute pane displays the text area control attributes.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click <uicontrol>TextArea &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol>, and then enter a title.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Height</uicontrol> attribute, enter desired height. For example, you might enter <uicontrol>250px</uicontrol> for the address.</p>
                  <p>The text area is increased. Similarly, the width can also be specified.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Perform the following steps to add a drop-down list. </p>
            <p>You can specify the options for the drop-down list (using options) or retrieve from a data source, such as using the <uicontrol>Resource Types</uicontrol> catalog of the library.</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>SIMPLE INPUT CONTROLS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop into the <uicontrol>Employee Details</uicontrol> section. Drop the control within the confines of the section for the control to be displayed in the design area.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>DropDownList &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> in the design area. </p>
                  <p>The attribute pane displays the drop-down control attributes.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click <uicontrol>DropDownList &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol>, and enter a title for the list. </p>
                  <p>Alternatively, in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> attribute, enter a title for the list.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> attribute, enter a reference title for the database.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note> No spacing is allowed in the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> attribute and it must be unique for this form.</note>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>DataSource</uicontrol> attribute, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline"/>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Data Source Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.<ol>
                        <li>To specify any options, update the <uicontrol>Display</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> options in the <uicontrol>ListItems</uicontrol> section. </li>
                        <li>Optionally, click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> button to add rows.</li>
                        <li>
                           <p>To pull information from a data source, perform the following actions:<ol>
                                 <li>From the <uicontrol>Select a Module</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the module, such as <uicontrol>Library</uicontrol>. </li>
                                 <li>From the <uicontrol>Select a Form</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the form, such as <uicontrol>Resource Types</uicontrol>. </li>
                                 <li>From the <uicontrol>Select Display</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the display, such as <uicontrol>ResourceType</uicontrol>. </li>
                                 <li>From the <uicontrol>Select Value</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the value, such as <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol>. <p>The string, such as <uicontrol>LIBRARYResourceType;ResourceType;Description</uicontrol>, is displayed in the <uicontrol>Query String</uicontrol> box. </p>
                                    <p>In this example, data is imported from the <uicontrol>LIBRARYResourceType</uicontrol> table (data source).</p>
                                    <p>The <uicontrol>ResourceType</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> are the display and the value columns for the table respectively. </p>
                                 </li>
                                 <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.<p>The drop-down list is displayed in the form.</p>
                                 </li>
                              </ol>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To make a field required to be completed before allowing save on the form, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the design area, select the field.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the toolbar, click <uicontrol>Switch to Advanced</uicontrol> to make <uicontrol>Advanced Attributes</uicontrol> pane available.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Expand the <uicontrol>Advanced Attributes</uicontrol> pane.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Validations</uicontrol> attribute, enter <uicontrol>Required</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>Alternatively,<p>In the <uicontrol>Validations</uicontrol> attribute, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                           <alt>List</alt>
                        </image>, and in the <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> dialog box, enter <uicontrol>Required</uicontrol>, and then click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </p>
                     <p>A '*' mark is displayed corresponding to the field indicating it is a mandatory field.</p>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Perform the following steps to create a control within the form that is visible based on specific conditions. For example, wanting to record years of experience for an employee, but only if the employee is experienced.</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>First introduce a <uicontrol>Radio Button List</uicontrol> control.</p>
                  <p>In this example it is to specify if the employee is experienced.</p>
                  <p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>Simple Input Controls</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Radio Button List</uicontrol> into the section.</li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>Radio Button List</uicontrol> in the design area. <p>The attribute pane displays the radio button control attributes. </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> attributes, enter a title. For example, enter <uicontrol>Experienced</uicontrol>. </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>DataSource</uicontrol> attribute, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                              <alt>List</alt>
                           </image>. <p>The <uicontrol>Data Source Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Display</uicontrol> column, enter the appropriate options. <p>For example, enter <uicontrol>Yes</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>No</uicontrol> for <uicontrol>Option 1</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Option 2</uicontrol> respectively.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Perform the following steps to create a numeric text box control. For our example, it enables the user to enter the number of years of experience.</p>
                  <p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>Simple Input Controls</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Numeric</uicontrol> to the design area and within the confines of the section. </li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>Numeric</uicontrol> in the design area. <p>The attribute pane displays the numeric control attributes.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> attribute, enter a title for the field. For example, enter <uicontrol>Years of Experience</uicontrol>.</li>
                        <li>In the toolbar, click <uicontrol>Switch to Advanced</uicontrol>. </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Advanced Attributes</uicontrol> pane, scroll down to <uicontrol>VisibleIf</uicontrol>, and then type $&lt;control name&gt;=&lt;value&gt;. For our example, enter <uicontrol>$Experienced=1</uicontrol>. <p>This implies if the value of the Radio Button control named <uicontrol>Experienced</uicontrol> is selected as <uicontrol>Yes</uicontrol>, that is assigned a value of 1, then the control <uicontrol>Years of Experience</uicontrol> will be visible.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Perform the following steps to insert a <uicontrol>Static Grid</uicontrol> control: </p>
            <p>
               <note> In a static grid the number of rows and columns are fixed and are used in scenarios where data to be entered can be limited to the available numbers of rows and columns. For example, if you wanted two references for an employee.</note>
            </p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>CHILD DATA CONTAINERS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Static Grid</uicontrol> to the design area and outside the confines of the section. </p>
                  <p>A dialog box to specify the number of rows and columns is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Enter the numbers for the number of rows and columns, and then click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Static Grid</uicontrol> is inserted.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>STATICGRID &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> in the design area. </p>
                  <p>The attribute pane displays the static grid control attributes.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click <uicontrol>STATICGRID &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> in the design area, and then enter a grid title. For example, enter <uicontrol>References</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>Alternatively, <p>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> attribute, enter a grid title.</p>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click each column name in the static grid and enter column headers. For example, enter <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Company</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Designation</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Contact Information</uicontrol> for the <uicontrol>Reference</uicontrol> example.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To create a picker to the form, first you must add a <uicontrol>Picker</uicontrol> and then add a <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Picker Trigger</uicontrol>. To add a <uicontrol>Picker</uicontrol>, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>CHILD DATA CONTAINERS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop the <uicontrol>Picker</uicontrol> into the <uicontrol>Form</uicontrol> area (not within any section).</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Data Source Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Select a Module</uicontrol> drop-down list, select a module. For example, select <uicontrol>Library</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Select a Form</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the form that the data will be drawn from. For example, select <uicontrol>Enterprise Resource Directory</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Display Column</uicontrol>, select the column for data selection. For example, select <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>From the <uicontrol>Key Column</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the column for data selection. For example, select <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Add Column To Display</uicontrol> drop down list, select columns to display in picker. For example, select <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Resource Type</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Working Hours</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Add Columns To Sort By</uicontrol>, select the columns in the order they should display in the picker. For example, select <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Resource Type</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Working Hours</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>Based on the options selected, in the <uicontrol>Query String</uicontrol> field, a string is displayed.</p>
                  <p>Based on the examples, <uicontrol>{Table:LIBRARYEnterpriseResourceDirectory;ID,Name,ResourceType,WorkingHours}</uicontrol> is displayed. </p>
                  <p>In this example, the data is imported from the <uicontrol>Enterprise Resource Directory</uicontrol> table. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>Picker reference appears in form section.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To add a <uicontrol>Set and a Picker Trigger</uicontrol> inside the <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol>, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>Advanced Controls</uicontrol>, then drag and drop the <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> into a section.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click on <uicontrol>Set 000</uicontrol> and enter the title. For example, enter <uicontrol>Resource Name</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Common Attributes</uicontrol>, click on the <uicontrol>SetTitlesToLeft</uicontrol>, and then select <uicontrol>True</uicontrol>. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> attribute, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image> . </p>
                  <p>A <uicontrol>Value Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Select Resolver</uicontrol> drop-down list, select <uicontrol>Picker</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Select Picker</uicontrol> field, select the previously created picker. </p>
                  <p>For our example, select <uicontrol>Picker000</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Select Column</uicontrol> field, select any of the fields added in the selected picker. </p>
                  <p>For example, select <uicontrol>Picker000.Name</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>Based on the selections, a <uicontrol>Resolver</uicontrol> string is displayed.</p>
                  <p>In our example, <uicontrol>{_Picker:Picker000.Name}</uicontrol> is displayed. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>To edit the <uicontrol>TextBox ###</uicontrol> information, click on the field square.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Common Attributes</uicontrol>, click <uicontrol>Caption</uicontrol> to edit the title. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>Advanced Controls</uicontrol>, then drag and drop the <uicontrol>Picker Trigger</uicontrol> into the section below the set.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Common Attributes</uicontrol>, select <uicontrol>PickerName</uicontrol>, and then click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline"/>.</p>
                  <p> The <uicontrol>Select Picker</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Select Picker</uicontrol> field, select the picker. For our example, select <uicontrol>Picker000</uicontrol>.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Select Unique Column ID</uicontrol> field, select a column. For our example, select <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>
                     <note> The field selected must have unique records, such as the <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol> field.</note>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The form page is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>PickerButtonText</uicontrol> attribute, enter … (three dots).</p>
                  <p>The picker trigger should now show the same in the design area. </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Drag the <uicontrol>Picker Trigger</uicontrol> and place it inside the <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol>. </p>
                  <p>The picker trigger of <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                        <alt>List</alt>
                     </image> button is displayed at end of <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> field.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To create an automatically generated code with a sequential number, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the controls pane, click <uicontrol>SIMPLE INPUT CONTROLS</uicontrol>, and then drag and drop <uicontrol>Auto Generated</uicontrol> into the section.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Double-click <uicontrol>AutoIncrement &lt;number&gt;</uicontrol> and enter a title. For example, enter <uicontrol>Record ID</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane displays the auto-generated attributes.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>To provide a format for the field entry, perform the following steps:</p>
                  <p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> pane, in the <uicontrol>NumberingLogic</uicontrol>, click <image href="../../../Icons/select.png" placement="inline">
                              <alt>List</alt>
                           </image>.<p>The <uicontrol>Numbering Logic Editor</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Number of Digits</uicontrol> box, enter the number of digits for the auto-generated number.<p>For example, selecting <uicontrol>3</uicontrol> will show auto-generated section numbering in three digits, such as <uicontrol>001</uicontrol>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Interval </uicontrol>box, enter the interval of numbers to be generated. For example, an interval of <uicontrol>2</uicontrol> generates numbers in sequence like 2, 4, 6, and so on.</li>
                        <li>
                           <p>To identify a column that if the value is changed should trigger a reset back to starting number, open a drop-down in the <uicontrol>Reset Number</uicontrol> field, and then select the column name. For example, if you had two <uicontrol>Resource Types</uicontrol> of <uicontrol>Full-time</uicontrol> and<uicontrol> Part-time</uicontrol>, you might want each type's numbering to start at 1.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>To provide additional elements, such as a static prefix or suffix to the auto-generated number, perform the following steps: </p>
                  <p>for example <uicontrol>EMP-&lt;&lt;ResourceType&gt;&gt;-&lt;&lt;1&gt;&gt;</uicontrol>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>.</li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> column, select the type of element. <uicontrol>Fixed</uicontrol> is a static text. Autopopulated would pull information from an identified data source. Autogenerated would be the numbering identified in this editor.</li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column, enter or select the value for type. <p>This displays <uicontrol>EMP</uicontrol> as the beginning of the employee code.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Separator</uicontrol> column, select the required separator. <p>For the example above, you can fill the table as:<ul>
                                 <li>First row: Type = Fixed, Value = EMP, Separator = - </li>
                                 <li>Second row: Type = Autopopulated, Value = ResourceType, Separator = -</li>
                                 <li>Third row: Type = Autogenerated, Value = 1 [or alternative starting number], Separator = -</li>
                              </ul>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. </li>
                     </ol>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>FORMS LIST</uicontrol> page is displayed. </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the list page, select the appropriate form, and then click <uicontrol>Publish</uicontrol>. </p>
            <p>The form is now available in the application.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To verify if the form is published, perform the following steps: </p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>Navigate to the module where the form is published; <uicontrol>Library</uicontrol> for the example described here. </p>
                  <p>The form is available in the navigation pane.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the navigation pane, click the form. </p>
                  <p>The form list page is displayed.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> to display a new form.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Enter the details, and then click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to save the form.</p>
                  <p>After a form is created and published: <ul>
                        <li>
                           <p>You can associate a workflow to the form.</p>
                           <p>For information on associating a workflow to the form, refer to <xref href="../../../Common_Application_Features/Workflow_Management/AssociateWF.xml"/>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p>You will need to assign permissions to the form.</p>
                           <p>For information on defining role-based permissions to the form, refer to <xref href="../../User_Management/Permissions/ConfigRolePerms.xml">Configuring Role Permissions</xref>.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ul>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note> If the form is located in the library, you do not need to assign permissions as all library catalogs have the same permissions.</note>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </body>
</topic>
