<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="AdminConfigRolePerms">
   <title>Configuring Role Permissions</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="administrator,engineering,management,external contractors,analyst"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>permission-configuration</indexterm>
            <!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>role-management</indexterm>
            <!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>form-permissions</indexterm>
            <!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>admin-console</indexterm>
            <!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>access-control</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>configure-role-permissions</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>assign-form-perms</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>validate-permissions</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>save-permissions</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>audit-permissions</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>mind-administration-guide</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>capital-program-management</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>form-security</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>web-admin-portal</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>user-access-management</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>Mind-Administration-Guide</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="Configuring Role Permissions"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="You can assign permissions to a role for each of the forms available in the application; the guide shows where to find the Administration page and how to save changes."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities" content="role;form;permission;access-control-list"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:capital-program-management;usecase:configure-role-permissions;industry:glass-manufacturing"/>
         <othermeta name="tags" content="permissions,role,forms,configuration"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase" content="configure-role-permissions"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <context>You can assign permissions to a role for each of the forms available in the application. <p>You can also configure<xref href="ConfigPermis-Bulk.xml">role permissions in bulk using an Excel workbook</xref>.</p>
      </context>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>In the module menu, click<uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>ADMINISTRATION</uicontrol>page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the navigation pane, expand<uicontrol>User Management</uicontrol>, and then click<uicontrol>Permissions</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>PERMISSIONS</uicontrol>page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To set permissions for a role, in the<uicontrol>By Roles</uicontrol>tab, from the<uicontrol>Roles</uicontrol>drop-down list, select the requiredrole to assign permissions.</p>
            <p>Available options are all roles created in the application. <ph product="Exclude_PG_Content">For information on creating a role, refer to<xref href="../Security_Roles/CreateRole.xml">Creating a Security Role</xref>.</ph>
            </p>
            <p>Alternatively, type the name of the role, and then select the required role.</p>
            <p>Available options are role names that match the entered role name. <ph product="Exclude_PG_Content">For information on creating a role, refer to<xref href="../Security_Roles/CreateRole.xml">Creating a Security Role</xref>.</ph>
            </p>
            <p>The permissions for the selectedrole are available in the<uicontrol>Form Permissions</uicontrol> tab.</p>
            <p>
               <note> If you select the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> check boxes, the <uicontrol>View</uicontrol> check box is automatically selected. However, when you clear the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> check boxes, the <uicontrol>View</uicontrol> check box is not cleared automatically. </note>
               <note> The first check box row in the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> columns displays:<ul>
                     <li>
                        <image width=".5cm" href="../../../Icons/AllSelect.png" placement="inline">
                           <alt>Create Check All</alt>
                        </image> - indicates that permission is granted to all the roles or forms that are available in the permission matrix</li>
                     <li>
                        <image width=".5cm"
                               href="../../../Icons/NoneSelect.png"
                               placement="inline">
                           <alt>Check Box</alt>
                        </image>- indicates that permission is not granted to any of the roles or forms that are available in the permission matrix</li>
                     <li>
                        <image href="../../../Icons/Indeterminate-checkbox.jpg" placement="inline">
                           <alt>Edit Check All</alt>
                        </image> - indicates that permission is granted to some of the roles or forms that are available in the permission matrix</li>
                  </ul>
               </note>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To define permissions for forms, in the <uicontrol>Form Permissions</uicontrol> tab, perform any of the following procedures:</p>
            <p>
               <ul>
                  <li>Copy permissions from an existing role, and modify required permissions:<ol>
                        <li>From the <uicontrol>Copy Permissions From</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the required role to copy the permissions from.</li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>. <p>The form permissions of the selected role  are copied to the role selected in the <uicontrol>Roles</uicontrol> drop-down list.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>Optionally, select or clear the required permissions from the permission matrix to grant or revoke access.</li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>Select all or revoke all standard permissions for all forms, and modify required permissions:<ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> columns, select the check boxes in the top check box row to grant access or clear the check boxes to revoke access to the selected role.</li>
                        <li>Optionally, select or clear the required permissions from the permission matrix to grant or revoke access.</li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>Search for a specific form, and define permissions:<ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Module</uicontrol> column, in the search box, enter the name of the form, and then select the form.</li>
                        <li>In the corresponding row of the selected form, select or clear the check boxes in the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Others</uicontrol> columns  to set permissions.<p>Alternatively, to set the same permissions for all the forms that are displayed in the permission matrix, select or clear the check boxes in the row below the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> column.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>Select all or revoke all permissions of a form or module:<ol>
                        <li>In the Module column, select or clear the check box corresponding to a module or form. <ul>
                              <li>If the check box corresponding to a form is selected or cleared, all permissions on the form are granted or revoked.</li>
                              <li>If the check box corresponding to a module is selected or cleared, all permissions on all the forms in that module are granted or revoked.</li>
                           </ul>
                           <note> If you are assigning  permissions at the module level, the permissions are assigned to all the associated forms displayed in the permission matrix.  If a form is not displayed in the permission matrix, the permissions are not assigned to the form, even though the form is associated with the module.</note>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To set permissions for a report, click the <uicontrol>Report Permissions</uicontrol> tab, and perform any of the following procedures:</p>
            <p>
               <ul>
                  <li>Copy permissions from an existing role, and modify required permissions:<ol>
                        <li>From the <uicontrol>Copy Permissions From</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the required role to copy the permissions from.</li>
                        <li>Click <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>. <p>The report permissions for the selected role in the <uicontrol>Copy Permissions From</uicontrol> drop-down list are copied to the role selected in the <uicontrol>Roles</uicontrol> drop-down list.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>Optionally, select or clear the required permissions from the permission matrix to grant or revoke access.</li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>Select all or revoke all permissions of a report or module:<ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Module </uicontrol>column, select or clear the check box corresponding to a module or report. <ul>
                              <li>If the check box corresponding to a report is selected or cleared, all permissions on the report are granted or revoked.</li>
                              <li>If the check box corresponding to a module is selected or cleared, permissions on all the reports in that module are granted or revoked.</li>
                           </ul>
                           <note> If you are assigning  permissions at the module level, the permissions are assigned to all the associated reports displayed in the permission matrix.  If a report is not displayed in the permission matrix, the permissions are not assigned to the report, even though the report is associated with the module.</note>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>Search for a specific report, and define permissions: <ol>
                        <li>In the <uicontrol>Module</uicontrol> column, in the search box, enter the name of the report, and then select the report.</li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click<uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </body>
</topic>
