<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="t24803CF-BDF2-11F0-1227-09173F13E4C5" xml:lang="en">
   <title>To create a new Sync Group</title>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-24+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-24"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="production,maintenance,quality,safety,engineering,management"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>metr-365-power</indexterm>
            <indexterm>doc-manager</indexterm>
            <indexterm>doc-publisher</indexterm>
            <indexterm>doc-migration</indexterm>
            <indexterm>integration-api</indexterm>
            <indexterm>portal-admin</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>create-sync-group</indexterm>
            <indexterm>configure-objects</indexterm>
            <indexterm>map-fields</indexterm>
            <indexterm>permission-setup</indexterm>
            <indexterm>initial-ingest</indexterm>
            <indexterm>validation</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>revenue-lifecycle-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>revenue-lifecycle-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>production-environment</indexterm>
            <indexterm>quality-assurance</indexterm>
            <indexterm>crm-integration</indexterm>
            <indexterm>billing-cycle</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>metR-365-Power</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="To create a new sync group"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="How to create a new sync group: pick objects, map fields, set permissions, and run initial ingestion."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities"
                    content="sync-group;object;field;permission;ingest;mapping"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:revenue-operations;usecase:metadata-enrichment;industry:revenue-lifecycle-management"/>
         <othermeta name="tags"
                    content="create-sync-group,mapping,ingest,permissions,validation"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase" content="metadata-enrichment"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>Open the connector.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>From the left panel under Groups, select <uicontrol>Setup Sync Group</uicontrol>. </p>
            <stepresult>A list of existing sync groups is displayed (if this is the first time you
               are using the tool, there will be no sync groups in the list).</stepresult>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>From the top of the page, click <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>. </p>
            <stepresult>The New Sync Group window is displayed.</stepresult>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Enter a <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> for the sync group.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Specify <uicontrol>Is Active </uicontrol>= <uicontrol>Yes</uicontrol> to enable scheduled sync for this sync group. If <uicontrol>No</uicontrol> is selected, sync group automation is disabled (scheduler flow remains unaffected).</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click the type ahead next to <uicontrol>Source </uicontrol>and search-and-select the source connection (Dynamics 365 or Power).</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click the type-ahead next to <uicontrol>Destination</uicontrol> and search-and-select the target connection (Dynamics 365 or Power).</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To configure a scheduler for executing data sync for this sync group complete the following fields:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol>Sync Frequency </uicontrol>and select the frequency for the sync job to execute: Minute, Hour, Day, Week, or Month.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click <uicontrol> Sync Interval </uicontrol>and enter a number to designate the interval for the frequency you selected (for example, selecting "Hour" for frequency and "6" for interval creates a scheduler to sync the objects in the sync group every 6 hours).</p>
                  <p>
                     <note type="warning">
                        <ul>
                           <li>For existing customers, adding the sync frequency and interval will automatically set up scheduled data sync for that sync group. If you previously created a scheduler using a Dynamics process, you must delete that process for scheduled syncs to execute successfully.</li>
                           <li>The minimum interval allowed by Dynamics 365 is 3 minutes.</li>
                        </ul>
                     </note>
                  </p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. The Sync Objects table is now displayed below the form.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>New Object Sync</uicontrol>. The New Object Sync page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Enter the <uicontrol>Object</uicontrol>
               <uicontrol>Mapping Name</uicontrol> of the object to be added to the sync group (for example, "clm_agreement mapping"). </p>
            <p>
               <note type="note">
                  <p>You cannot add the same object to another Sync Group that is syncing in the same direction (for example, from Power to Dynamics 365).</p>
               </note>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Enter a number in the <uicontrol>Sync Sequence</uicontrol> field to specify the order in which the object and its fields should be synced. This is useful when you have a master-child relationship or lookup relation and you need to sync objects in a specific order to avoid errors or missing data. Begin the Sequence by entering "1."</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Enter an AQL query in <uicontrol>Source Filter Criteria</uicontrol> to apply a filter to the object data in the sync (Example filter: {"ExpressionOperator": "OR","Conditions": [{"EntityName": "apttus_apts_agreement", "FieldName": "apttus_name", "FilterOperator": "Like", "Value": "TestFilter%" }]}).</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. The sync group is created with the object mapping you selected for the source and destination. The page refreshes and the Fields Sync Information section is displayed below the form.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Add mapped fields from the sync group object by clicking on the <uicontrol>Add </uicontrol>
               <image placement="inline"
                      width="20"
                      href="../attachments/143888191/143888189.png"/>
               icon to move Available Fields in the left column to Selected Fields to Sync in the right column. To remove a field from the sync group, click the <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol>
               <image placement="inline"
                      width="20"
                      href="../attachments/143888191/143888190.png"/>
               icon.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>From the top of the Fields Sync Information section, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Repeat steps 10 – 16  to add more mapped objects to the sync group.</p>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </body>
</topic>
