<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="Form_DELAUTH_New">
   <title>Delegating Authorities</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-20"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="administrator,engineering,management,external contractors,analyst"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>delegation</indexterm>
            <indexterm>delegate-module</indexterm>
            <indexterm>approval-rule</indexterm>
            <indexterm>user-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>user-account</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>delegate-approval</indexterm>
            <indexterm>create-rule</indexterm>
            <indexterm>edit-rule</indexterm>
            <indexterm>approve-on-behalf</indexterm>
            <indexterm>reassign-approvals</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>mind-administration-guide</indexterm>
            <indexterm>capital-program-management</indexterm>
            <indexterm>infrastructure-software</indexterm>
            <indexterm>access-governance</indexterm>
            <indexterm>user-provisioning</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>Mind-Administration-Guide</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="Delegation of Authority"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="When a user is unavailable or unable to perform tasks in the system, delegation allows another user to act on their behalf for approvals and actions."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities"
                    content="delegation;delegate module;approval rule;user;user account"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:Capital-program-management;usecase:delegate;industry:glass-manufacturing"/>
         <othermeta name="tags" content="user,delegate,approval,delegation,authority"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase" content="delegate"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <prereq>
         <ul>
            <li>The delegated user must have the same role as the original activity owner.</li>
            <li>The delegated user must not be invited to the project.</li>
         </ul>
      </prereq>
      <context>
         <p>The <uicontrol>Delegation of Authority</uicontrol> form enables you to assign roles and projects of one user to another user of the same role. The process of delegating authority includes the following tasks in the order specified:</p>
         <ol>
            <li>Select the user from whom you want to delegate activities</li>
            <li>Select the role you want to delegate</li>
            <li>Select the user to whom you want to delegate activities of the selected role</li>
            <li>Select the dates within which the delegated user must remain invited to the projects or contracts</li>
            <li>Assign projects and contracts to the delegated user</li>
            <li>Save the record</li>
         </ol>
      </context>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>In the module menu, click<uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>ADMINISTRATION</uicontrol>page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the navigation pane, expand<uicontrol>User Management</uicontrol>, and then click<uicontrol>Delegation of Authority</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY</uicontrol>list page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click<uicontrol>New</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The<uicontrol>DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY</uicontrol>page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the <uicontrol>Delegate From User</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the user from whom you want to delegate activities.
</p>
            <p>Available options are all active users in the application.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To provide information of the user to whom you want to delegate authority and the role for delegation, in the <uicontrol>DELEGATE A ROLE</uicontrol> section, perform the following steps: </p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>User Role</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the role of the user fromwhom you want to delegate activities.</p>
                  <p>Available user roles are the unique roles the user selected in the<uicontrol>Delegate From User</uicontrol>field currently has in the application.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Delegate To User</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the user to whom you want to delegate activities. Alternatively, type the name of the user, and then select the required user.</p>
                  <p>Available users are:<ul>
                        <li>Users who have the same role as the role selected in the<uicontrol>User Role</uicontrol>field</li>
                        <li>All the active users not invited to the projects that the user selected in the<uicontrol>Delegate From User</uicontrol>field is part of</li>
                     </ul>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>From Date</uicontrol>  drop-down list, select the date on which the user selected in the <uicontrol>Delegate To User</uicontrol> field is to be invited to the projects or contracts.
 

</p>
                  <p/>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>To Date</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the date until which the delegated user must remain invited to the projects or contracts. 
</p>
                  <p>The system revokes the delegated user's invitation to the project by the end of the day on the selected date.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> box, enter any notes for the delegation of authority.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To assign projects to the delegated user, in the <uicontrol>PROJECT SELECTION</uicontrol> section, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>Click<uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The<uicontrol>Projects List</uicontrol>dialog box is displayed.</p>
                  <p>Available options are the projects the transferer is part of with the role selected in the<uicontrol>User Role</uicontrol> field.</p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Select the appropriateprojects, and then click<uicontrol>Select</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The<uicontrol>Project Code</uicontrol> and the<uicontrol>Project Name</uicontrol> values are displayed.</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To assign contracts to the delegated user, in the <uicontrol>CONTRACT SELECTION</uicontrol> section, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>
                  <p>Click<uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The<uicontrol>Contracts List</uicontrol>dialog box is displayed.</p>
                  <p>Available options are contracts based on the following:- <ul>
                        <li>Projects selected in the<uicontrol>PROJECT SELECTION</uicontrol>section</li>
                        <li>Role of the user selected in the<uicontrol>User Role</uicontrol> field for the user selected in the <uicontrol>Delegate From User</uicontrol>field</li>
                     </ul>
                  </p>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <p>Click the appropriate contract, and then click<uicontrol>Select</uicontrol>.</p>
                  <p>The<uicontrol>Project Code</uicontrol>,<uicontrol>Project Name</uicontrol>,<uicontrol>Contract Code</uicontrol>, and<uicontrol>Contract Name</uicontrol>of the associated project are displayed</p>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click<uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
         </li>
      </ol>
      <result>Based on the <uicontrol>From Date</uicontrol> selected, the saved record can be in any of the following statuses:<ul>
            <li>Awaited - The status indicates that the delegation is yet to be executed on a future date.</li>
            <li>Delegated - The status indicates that the delegation is executed. </li>
            <li>Failure - The status indicates that the delegation is failed due to discrepancies in data.</li>
         </ul>Based on the <uicontrol>To Date</uicontrol> selected, the saved record can be in any of the following statuses:<ul>
            <li>Revoked - The status indicates that the delegation is revoked on the <uicontrol>To Date</uicontrol> selected</li>
            <li>Failure - The status indicates that the delegation is failed due to discrepancies in data.</li>
         </ul>
      </result>
   </body>
</topic>
