<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="Mod_Dynamic_Msg_Diff_Form">
   <title>Modifying Dynamic Messages by Inserting a Field of Different Form</title>
   <shortdesc/>
   <prolog>
      <author>Yashshree</author>
      <critdates>
         <created date="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
         <revised modified="2025-11-20+05:30"/>
      </critdates>
      <metadata>
         <audience type="role"
                   otherprops="administrator,engineering,management,external contractors,analyst"/>
         <keywords><!-- Product layer -->
            <indexterm>error-message-configurator</indexterm>
            <indexterm>dynamic-message-engine</indexterm>
            <indexterm>message-template</indexterm>
            <indexterm>message-bundle</indexterm>
            <indexterm>message-editor</indexterm>
            <!-- Process layer -->
            <indexterm>modify-error-messages</indexterm>
            <indexterm>edit-message</indexterm>
            <indexterm>update-template</indexterm>
            <indexterm>configure-message</indexterm>
            <indexterm>map-fields</indexterm>
            <!-- Context layer -->
            <indexterm>dynamic-messages</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form-field</indexterm>
            <indexterm>placeholder-variables</indexterm>
            <indexterm>google-blockly</indexterm>
            <indexterm>form-validation</indexterm>
         </keywords>
         <prodinfo>
            <prodname>Mind-Administration-Guide</prodname>
            <platform>web</platform>
         </prodinfo>
         <othermeta name="title" content="Modifying Dynamic Messages of Different Form"/>
         <othermeta name="shortdesc"
                    content="Explains how to modify dynamic error messages for different forms using the message editor and Blockly integrations."/>
         <othermeta name="language" content="en-GB"/>
         <othermeta name="version" content="1.0.0"/>
         <othermeta name="docStage" content="approved"/>
         <othermeta name="access.role" content="internal"/>
         <othermeta name="data.classification" content="non-sensitive"/>
         <othermeta name="retention.policy" content="standard-36m"/>
         <othermeta name="entities"
                    content="placeholder;variable;blockly;form-field;message-template"/>
         <othermeta name="taxonomy"
                    content="domain:capital-program-management;usecase:modify-dynamic-messages;industry:glass-manufacturing"/>
         <othermeta name="tags"
                    content="dynamic-messages,placeholders,blockly,template-editing,message-modification"/>
         <othermeta name="usecase"
                    content="edit dynamic error messages and manage placeholder variables for different forms"/>
      </metadata>
   </prolog>
   <body>
      <context>You can modify dynamic messages by inserting a field of different form through UI using <uicontrol>Insert Other Form Field</uicontrol> option. You can also modify the variables in the dynamic messages using Google Blockly (Blockly).</context>
      <ol>
         <li>
            <p>In the module menu, click <uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>ADMINISTRATION</uicontrol> page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the navigation pane, expand the <uicontrol>Configuration Toolkit</uicontrol> folder, and then click <uicontrol>Error Message Configurator</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>ERROR MESSAGE CONFIGURATOR</uicontrol> list page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>In the <uicontrol>ERROR MESSAGE CONFIGURATOR</uicontrol> list page, select the appropriate error message, and then click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>ERROR MESSAGE CONFIGURATOR</uicontrol> page is displayed.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Based on the error message in the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> field, rewrite the error message in the <uicontrol>New Error Message</uicontrol> field. </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Place the cursor where the dynamic variable must be inserted in the <uicontrol>New Error Message</uicontrol> field.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Insert Other Form Field</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>A pop-up is displayed where you can search and retrieve the fields from other modules or forms.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>To search and retrieve the appropriate field information from other modules or forms, perform the following steps: </p>
            <p>
               <ol>
                  <li outputclass="break_avoid">Click <uicontrol>Read Data</uicontrol>.<note>The <uicontrol>Read Data</uicontrol> feature retrieves the appropriate information from other modules or forms using a reference field that is common between the source and the destination form.</note>
                     <p>The following screen is displayed on the right pane of the screen. <fig>
                           <title/>
                           <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Read_Data.jpg"
                                  placement="inline"/>
                        </fig>
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>To search the appropriate information from the destination form, in the <uicontrol>SELECT</uicontrol> field, define the appropriate values in the <uicontrol>Select Module</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Select Form</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Select Field</uicontrol>.<note>The <uicontrol>SELECT</uicontrol> field searches for the defined values in the <uicontrol>Select Field</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Select Form</uicontrol> that belongs to the <uicontrol>Select Module</uicontrol> entities.</note>
                  </li>
                  <li>To define the relationship between the destination form and the source form, in the <uicontrol>WHERE</uicontrol> field, define the appropriate values in the <uicontrol>Select Module</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Select Form</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Select Field</uicontrol>.<note>
                        <ul>
                           <li>The <uicontrol>WHERE</uicontrol> field acts as the reference identifier between the source and the destination form.</li>
                           <li>The <uicontrol>WHERE</uicontrol> field retrieves the defined values from the <uicontrol>Select Field</uicontrol> of the <uicontrol>Select Form</uicontrol> that belongs to the <uicontrol>Select Module</uicontrol> entities.</li>
                        </ul>
                     </note>
                  </li>
                  <li>To define the identifier of the record, click <uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol>, and then use the appropriate filters as applicable:<note> Once added, you can remove the filter by dragging and dropping it to <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Delete_icon.png"
                               placement="inline"/> in the center right corner of the screen.</note>
                     <ul>
                        <li>
                           <uicontrol>Get Value of</uicontrol>: To retrieve a list of identifiers from the source form, perform the following steps:<ol>
                              <li outputclass="break_avoid">Drag and drop the <uicontrol>Get Value of</uicontrol> filter in the double quoted empty field.<note>The <uicontrol>Get Value of</uicontrol> filter defines which identifier or reference field should be validated from the source form to retrieve a field from the destination form.</note>
                                 <fig>
                                    <title/>
                                    <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Read_Data_GetValue_Filter.jpg"
                                           placement="inline"/>
                                 </fig>
                              </li>
                              <li outputclass="break_avoid">Place the cursor in the empty field adjacent to the <uicontrol>Get Value of</uicontrol> filter.<p>The <uicontrol>Search Fields</uicontrol> bar is displayed.<fig>
                                       <title/>
                                       <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Get_Value_Of_Search_Field.jpg"
                                              placement="inline"/>
                                    </fig>
                                 </p>
                              </li>
                              <li>To add fields to the <uicontrol>Get Value of</uicontrol> filter, search the field name in the <uicontrol>Search Fields</uicontrol> bar, and select the appropriate field when it is displayed.</li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li outputclass="break_avoid">
                           <uicontrol>Resolve Value of</uicontrol>: To retrieve the common attributes between the source and the destination form, perform the following steps: <ol>
                              <li outputclass="break_avoid">Drag and drop the <uicontrol>Resolve Value of</uicontrol> filter in the double quoted empty field.<note> The <uicontrol>Resolve Value of</uicontrol> filter consists of <uicontrol>Parent Module Id</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Module ID</uicontrol>, Project details, and user details that are used as identifiers.</note>
                                 <fig>
                                    <title/>
                                    <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Read_Data_Select_Resolver_Filter.jpg"
                                           placement="inline"/>
                                 </fig>
                              </li>
                              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Select Resolver</uicontrol> field adjacent to the <uicontrol>Resolve Value of</uicontrol> filter.<fig>
                                    <title/>
                                    <image href="../../../Icons/Screenshots_Icons/Select_Resolver.jpg"
                                           placement="inline"/>
                                 </fig>
                              </li>
                              <li outputclass="break_avoid">From the <uicontrol>Select Resolver</uicontrol> drop-down list, select the appropriate attributes. </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                     </ul>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. </p>
            <p>The selected variables are added to the appropriate place in the <uicontrol>New Error Message</uicontrol> field.<p>Alternatively, you can click <uicontrol>Restore</uicontrol> to modify the values.</p>
            </p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p>The modified error message is displayed in the <uicontrol>ERROR MESSAGE CONFIGURATOR</uicontrol> list page for the respective record.</p>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </body>
</topic>
